We come in peace for cats and mice everywhere.
我们为所有的猫和老鼠带来和平
Hey, how you doing? Good to see you. Thanks for coming out.
你们好，幸会了
Boring!
无聊死了 !
Dad, we can’t see the movie.
和葡， 我们看不到啦
I can’t believe we're paying to see something we get on TV for free.
电视免费，我们却付钱来看这个
If you ask me, everybody in this theater is a giant sucker.
照我看， 这戏院里的人都是呆子
Especially you.
特别是你
Movie on the big screen!
《辛普森一家电影版》
Excuse me. My heinie is dipping.
抱歉，我屁股往下沉了
All right, well, thanks a lot for coming.
谢谢大家
We've been playing for three and a half hours.
我们已经唱了三个半小时了
Now we'd like just a minute of your time to say something about the environment.
现在我们想花一分钟来谈环保
-You suck! -Shut up and play!
-无聊 ! -闭嘴，快唱啦 !
-Preachy! -We're not being preachy.
-爱说教! -我们不是在说教
But the pollution in your lake, it’s dissolving our barge.
污染的湖水 正在溶解我们的舞台
I thought they touched on a vital issue.
他们提到了很重要的议题
I beg to differ.
拜托
Gentlemen, it’s been an honor playing with you tonight.
各位，很荣幸能与你们同台演出
For the latest rock band to die in our town...
对于最近匡身于镇上的摇滚乐团
...Lord, hear our prayer.
主啊，请听我们祷告
I hate being late.
我讨厌迟到
Well, I hate going.
我讨厌来
Why can’t I worship the Lord . In my own way...
为啥不能在家崇拜主
...by praying like hell on my deathbed?
到死前再祷告 ?
Homer, they can hear you inside.
荷马，他们会听见的
Relax. Those pious morons are too busy talking to their phony-baloney God.
放心啦， 那些假道学的笨蛋 都忙着在求他们骗人的上帝
How you doing? Peace be with you. Praise Jebus.
你们好，祝你平安' 赞美耶稣
Today I'd like to try something a little different.
今天 ' 我想来点不一样的
I'm going to call on one of you!
我要请你们其中之一说话
Now, the word of God dwells within everyone.
上帝的话语在每个人心中
l want you to let that word out. Let your spirit--
我要你说出那番话语，让你的精神…
What is it, Ned?
怎么了' 奈德 ?
The good Lord is telling me to confess to something.
上帝叫我要坦白
Gay, gay, gay.
出柜、出柜、出柜
An immodest sense of pride in our community.
我对本社区太过于骄傲了
Somebody else?
还有其他人吗 ?
Let the Lord's light shine upon you.
让上帝的光芒照亮你
Feel the spirit.
感受圣灵
Let it out!
说出来吧 !
Horrible, horrible things are going to happen!
了恐怖，恐怖的事即将发生
And they’re gonna happen to you! And you! And you! And you.
那会发生在你们身上 还有你 ! 你 ! 和你
Whoa, nelly!
天哪 !
People of Springfield, heed this warning:
春田市的人们，听清楚了
Twisted tail!
搓曲之尾
A thousand eyes!
千眼之眼
Trapped forever!
终生受困
Dad, do something!
和葡，快想办法啊
This book doesn't have any answers!
这本书上没答案
Beware! Beware! Time is short!
注意 ! 注意 ! 时间不多 !
Believe me! Believe me!
相信我 ! 相信我 !
Thanks for listening.
多谢聆听
Okay, who wants waffles?
有谁要吃松饼啊 ?
Wait a minute. What about Grampa?
那爷从怎么办 ?
-l want syrup! -l want strawberries!
-我要加糖奖 -我要草莓
Something happened to that man.
他一定出事了
Ill tell you what happened to him. A certain someone had a senior moment.
我告诉你出了什么事吧 革人时就老人阁呆了呼
But that’s okay, because we love him and we got a free rug out of it.
不过没关系，因为我们爱他 还拿到一张免费地丢
What is the point of going to church every Sunday...
我们每个周日去教堂
...when if someone we love has a genuine religious experience, we ignore it?
当我们所爱的人真有了宗教体验 决不能视而不见
Right, Grampa?
对吧，等和爷?
l want bananas on my waffles.
我要加香碎
l rest my case.
我说完了
I'm not dropping this.
我不会就此放弃
Wait a minute. I'm still in the car.
等一下，我还在车上
Oh, right.
是哦
“Take out hornets’ nest.”
“摘除马蜂窜”
Check. "Fix sinkhole.”
好了 ，“修好淘空地基”
Check.
好了
"Re-shingle roof"?
“重钉屋项” ?
Steady.
稳住
Why, you little--!
你这个小…
I'll teach you to laugh at something that’s funny!
我让你看看真正好笑的样子
You know, we are on the roof. We could have some fun.
我们在屋顶， 可以好好玩一下
What kind of fun?
玩什么?
How about a dare contest?
来比胆量吧
That sounds fun. I dare you to...
听起来很好玩，我财你…
..climb the TV antenna!
不敢疏上电视天线
-Piece of cake. -Earthquake!
-简单 -地震 !
Aftershock!
余震 !
Homer, I don’t mean to be a Nervous Pervis...
荷马，我不想太神经质
...but if he falls, couldn’t that make your boy a paraplege-arino?
不过要是他榨下来 你儿子不就竣了 ?
Shut up, Flanders.
闭嘴啦，佛朗德斯
Yeah, shut up, Flanders.
对啊，闭嘴啦
Well said, boy.
说得好，儿子
Steady....
稳住
Hello. Sorry to bother you on a Sunday...
你好， 抱歉在周日打扰您
...but I'm sure you're as worried about the pollution in Lake Springfield as I am.
但是我相信你很担心春田湖的污染
Lake Springfield has higher levels of mercury than ev--
春田湖的秒污染值已经超过…
Why, it’s the little girl who saved my cat.
你是那个救了我的猫的小女孩
Lake Springfield is--
春田湖已经…
Come on over, Lisa.
过来吧，莉范
You can canvass me as long as you want.
你想跟我说多久就说多久
Milhouse, you don't care about the environment.
米豪斯，你又不关心环境
Hey. I am very passionate about the planet.
我对地球充满热情
Say global warming is a myth.
说全球暖化是迷信
It's a myth! Further study is needed!
那是迷信 ! 需要进一步研究
That's for selling out your beliefs.
这是报答你出卖你的信念
Oh, poor Milhouse.
可怜的米豪斯
Dream coming true.
梦想成真了
Are you aware that a leaky faucet can waste over--?
你知道漏水的水龙头一年
Two thousand gallons a year.
会浪费超过两千加仑的水
-Turning off lights can save-- -Enough energy to power Pittsburgh.
-关掉你的灯所节省的电 -足以供应匹豆堡全市用电
And if we kept our thermostats at 68 in winter--
如果暖气都定在摄氏2 0 度
We'd be free from our dependency on foreign oil in 17 years.
我们可以1 了年都不用进口石油
I'm Colin.
我是柯林
l haven't seen you at school.
我在学校没见过你
Moved from Ireland. My dad's a musician.
刚从爱尔兰搬来，我爸是音乐家
-Is he...? -He’s not Bono.
-他是不是… ? -他不是波诺
-l just thought, because you're Irish and--
-我只是想因为你是爱尔兰人…
Do you play?
你会乐器吗 ?
Just piano, guitar, trumpet, drums and bass.
只会钢琴、吉他、喇叭、坑
He's pure gold. For once in your life, be cool.
他是金矿，拜托， 冷静点
So is your name as pretty as your face?
你的名字跟你的人一样美吗 ?
You okay there?
你没事吧 ?
Twisted tail! A thousand eyes! Trapped forever!
搓曲之尾、千眼之眼、终生受困
What could that be?
“饭包鼠”会是什么 ?
I believe it’s the sound the Green Lantern made...
我相信那是绿灯使
...when Sinestro threw him into a vat of acid.
被黄灯魔丢进硫酸桶时 发出的叫声
Yeah. Thanks for coming over.
是啊，谢谢你过来
Thanks for giving me your pregnancy pants.
多谢你送我你的孕妇裤
Never known comfort like this.
这才真的叫舒服
Why did I suggest this?
我于嘛起哄玩这个啊 ?
All right, boy, time for the ultimate dare.
好,儿子,该比终极胆量了
I dare you to skateboard to Krusty Burger and back...
我赌你不敢溜滑板去酷弟汉堡店
.. naked.
脱光去
-How naked? -Fourth base.
-多光? -三点全露
Girls might see my doodle.
那我的小弟弟会曝光
Oh, I see. Then I hereby declare you chicken for life.
我懂了“，那我宣布你是胆小鬼
Every morning, you'll wake up to "Good morning, chicken.”
你每天起床都会听到 “旱，胆小鬼”
At your wedding, I'll sing:
你结婚时我会唱…
Il like men now.
我爱男子汉
Don't look where I’m pointing!
别看我手指的地方
Stop in the name of American squeamishness!
看在美国人大惊小怪的份上快停
Boys, before we eat, don’t forget to thank the Lord for this bountiful--
用餐前要感谢上帝赐我们丰富的
Penis?!
小弟弟 ?
-Bountiful penis.
-丰富的小弟弟
Amen.
阿门
Listen, kid, nobody likes wearing clothes in public, but, you know, it’s the law.
孩子，没人喜欢穿衣服上街 不过这是法律规定
Lunchtime!
吃午饭了 !
You can't just leave me out here.
你们不能把我丢在这里
Don't worry, we found a friend for you to play with.
别担心，我们找到朋友陪你了
Nelson, honey, where have you been?
尼尔森 ' 小乖， 你跑哪去了 ?
-Dad! -What seems to be the problem, officers?
-和爸 ! -怎么回事， 警官 ?
Tell him you dared me to do it.
快说是你跟我打赌的
If that’s true, then you should be taking the rap here, not your son.
如果那是真的 受罚的就该是你， 不是你儿子
And what happens to me if it's my fault?
如果是我的错，我会怎样 ?
You'll have to attend a one-hour parenting class.
你得参加一小时的称职讲习
It was all his idea! He’s out of control, I tell you!
这全是他的主意 他彻底失控了
I'm at my wits’ end.
我毫无办法 !
It’s so....
这真是…
See you in court, kid.
法庭见了，小子
Okay, son, let’s get some lunch.
我们去吃饭吧，儿子
Did you at least bring my clothes?
你有带我的衣服来吗 ?
Shirt, socks, everything you need.
运动短袖、袜子…全都带了
-You didn’t bring my pants. -Who am I, Tommy Bahama?
-你没带我的裤子 ? -干嘛 ? 我又不是开服饰店
This is the worst day of my life.
今天是我这辈子最惨的一天
The worst day of your life so far.
是到目前为止最惨的一天
-Say, Bart? -What do you want, Flanders?
-霸子? -你想怎样，佛朗德斯 ?
If you need pants, I carry an extra pair.
你需要裤子的话，我有多带一条
You know how boys are, always praying through the knees.
你知道小孩总是喜欢跪下来祈祷
Why are you helping me? I'm not your kid.
为什么要帮我 ? 我又不是你儿子
We're neighbors. I’m sure your father would do the same for my boys.
我们是邻居 你父亲也会这么对待我孩子的
Thank you.
谢谢你
-Hey, what’s with you? -You really wanna know?
-你是怎样啦 ? -你想知道 ?
Of course I do.
当然
What kind of a father wouldn't care about--?
什么样的父亲会不关心… ?
A pig wearing a hat!
戴帽子的猪
Action.
开拍
Hey, hey! It’s your old pal Krusty, for my new pork sandwich, the Klogger.
我是你们的老朋友， 小丑酷弟 我新推出的猪排三明治 栓塞王
If you can find a greasier sandwich, you're in Mexico!
要想吃到更油腻的三明治 你就得去墨西哥啦
And we're clear.
拍好了
Perfect. Cut, print, kill the pig.
很好，卡，宁了这只猪
What--?! You can’t kill him if he’s wearing people clothes!
它穿着人的衣服，你不能杀它 我的眼里只有你…
You're coming home with me.
你跟我一起回家
"A thousand eyes.” What could that be?
“千眼之眼”到底是讲什么 ?
I'm pretty sure a thousand is a number.
我敢说“千”是个数字
Hey, Marge. Isn't it great being married to someone who's recklessly impulsive?
玛姬，有个冲动的老公很棒吧 ?
Actually, it's aged me horribly.
其实' 那让我老得更快
Then say hello to the newest Simpson.
跟新的辛普森家庭成员打招呼吧
Homer!
荷马!
I believe what happened in church was a warning about precisely this.
我相信教堂里发生的事 就是在警告这件事
Please, get rid of that pig.
快扔了那只猪
Oh, you're gonna love him. Look, he does an impression of you.
你会爱死它的 它的叫声跟你一样
You nailed her.
你超级像它
He also does me.
它也像我
You smiled. I'm off the hook.
你笑了“，我没事啦
Oh, you have so many looks.
你真是只百变魔猪
So that’s what snug is.
那才叫舒服
Who's a good pig?
谁是好猪猪啊 ?
Rough day, huh, son?
今天真不好过，是吧 ?
You don’t know what rough is, sister.
你才不懂什么叫不好过 姐妹
Bart, you know, whenever my boys bake up a batch of frownies, I take them fishing.
我的孩子不快乐的时候 我就带他们去钓鱼
Does your dad ever take you fishing?
你爸带你去过钓鱼吗 ?
Dad, it’s not fair to use a bug zapper to catch the fish.
和葡，用捕蚊灯捕鱼不太好吧
If you love fish like I do, you want them to die with dignity.
如果你跟我一样爱鱼 你就会希望他们死得痛快
I think I have a nibble.
我想我钓到了
I think fishing might be more fun with you.
我想跟你钓鱼可能比较好玩
Oh, great. Now, how about l fix you some cocoa?
太好了 ， 我弄杯可可给你喝如何 ?
No way. Cocoa’s for wusses.
不要，可可是弱者喝的
Well, sir, if you change your mind, it’s on the windowsill.
要是你改变主意，我就放在窗台上
Oh, my God.
天哪
Oh, wait. I didn’t tell you the best part. He loves the environment.
我还没跟你说最棒的…他爱环保
Oh, wait! I still didn’t tell you the best part. He’s got an Irish brogue.
等等，我还是没说最棒的部分 他说话有爱尔兰腔
No, no, wait! I still didn’t tell you the best part.
不，等等，我还是没说最棒的
He’s not imaginary!
他不是我想像出来的
Oh, honey, that's great.
女儿，那太好了
But the very best thing is that he listens to you.
不过最棒的是他听你说话
Because nothing means more than for a man to--
没有什么比得上一个男人…
How did the pig tracks get on the ceiling?
天花板上怎么会有猪脚印 ?
Spider-Pig, Spider-Pig
蜂蛛猪、蜂蛛猪
Does whatever a Spider-Pig does
蜂蛛猪行侠仗义
Can he swing from a web?
它能挂在蜂蛛网上吗 ?
No, he can't, he's a pig
不行，它是猪
Look out He is a Spider-Pig
小心，它是蜂蛛猪
Are we having fun yet?
我们在玩了吗 ?
We are now. You've got a bite.
已经开始了“，你钓到东西了
Whoa, mama!
妈呀 !
You're not strangling me.
你没来勒我的脖子
What the--? Strangling’s only good for....
什么 ? 勒脖子根本就…
Well, it's not good for anything.
一点好处都没有
The only time you should lay hands on a boy...
手放孩子身上只有一个用处
..jis to give him a good pat on the back.
就是拍拍他的背
Hey, what the hell are you--?
你于什么?
One more time.
再来一次
Honey, I’m home.
亲爱的，我回来了
We are at the tipping point, people.
我们正面临关键时刻
If we don’t do something now....
若现在不采取行动
I'm sorry, I lost my train of thought. Isn’t he dreamy?
我无法思考了“，他真是个白马王子
Agreed.
同意
Okay, so here's the bottom line:
所以这是最后底线了
If we don’t change our ways right now...
如果我们不立刻改变行为
...pollution in Lake Springfield will be at this level.
春田湖的污染会碳到这人么高
That's not so bad.
那还好嘛
No, the lift is stuck.
不， 升降机卡住了
Am I getting through to anyone?
有人明白了吗 ?
Hell, yeah. We need a new one of those things.
有 我们需要一台新的升降机
All in favor of a new scissor lift, say "aye."
同意买一台新升降机的说“好”
-Aye. -No!
-好 -不!
This lake is just one piece of trash away from a toxic nightmare.
这湖已濒临彻底毒化了
But I knew you wouldn't listen.
不过， 我早就知道你们听不进去
So I took the liberty of pouring water from the lake in all your drinking glasses.
所以我把湖水倒入你们的杯中
This is why we should hate kids.
小孩就是这样才令人讨厌
This is serious, people.
情况很严重，各位
No more dumping in the lake. I hereby declare a state of emergency.
湖里不准再倒垃圾了 我宣布进入紧急状态
Code black.
黑色警戒
Black? That’s the worst color there is.
黑色 ? 那是最精的颜色了
-No offense there, Carl. -I get it all the time.
-无意冒犯， 卡尔 -我习惯咯
Sorry, sorry. No dumping in the lake.
抱歉，湖里不准倒垃圾
Fine. I will put my yard trimmings in a car compactor.
好吧 我就把“废弃物”用压土机压扁
Chief, I think there was a dead body in there.
警长， 我想那是一具尸体
I thought that too, until he said "yard trimmings.”
我原本也这么想 但他说是“废弃物”
You gotta learn to listen, Lou.
你得注意听
Let us now make sure this barrier is completely idiot-proof.
确认一下路障连白阁都挡得住
-Cletus. -Yessum?
-呆子克 -是
Try to dump something in the lake.
倒点什么进湖里吧
Okay.
好
I can't. l simply can't.
不行，我做不到
-Brilliant. -Very effective.
-真聪明 -真有效
Don't get any ideas.
别乱想
Maybe we should kiss, just to break the tension.
也许我们该亲吻，拉近关系
What’s going on here?
这里是怎么回事 ?
Nothing. Nothing.
没什么
I'm not sure that pig should be in the house.
我不确定那只猪应该待在屋里
And by the way, what are you doing with his leavings?
还有， 你打算怎么处理它的…装 ?
Don't worry. I've devised a most elegant solution.
别担心，我想了一个最棒的方法
It’s leaking.
它漏出来了
It’s not leaking, it's overflowing.
那不是漏，是满出来了
He filled up the whole silo in just two days?
才两天它就装满了整简凌 ?
Well, I helped.
我也有和贡献啦
Homer, stop! Stop. I know it’s easy for your mind to wander...
荷马,停 ! 我知道你很容易乱想
...but want you to really concentrate on me.
不过， 我要你专心听我说
I can’t escape the feeling that this is the crisis Grampa warned us about.
我无法不去想 这就是爷爷警告我们的危机
You have to dispose of that waste properly.
你得好好的处理那桶废弃物
Okay, Marge. I will.
好 ， 玛姬，我会的
You can take Spider-Pig with you.
你可以带你的由蛛猪跟你去
He’s not Spider-Pig anymore, he’s Harry Plopper.
它不是蜂蛛猪了，它是哈利猪特
Hello.
你好
Homer, you gotta get over here.
荷马，快来
Health inspector shut down the doughnut store, they're giving out free doughnuts!
卫生稽查员关了甜甜圈店 店家在免费大放送
Oh, my God, oh, my God! I just got one thing I gotta do first.
老天，我还有一件事要先搞定
Well, you better hurry. They’re going fast.
你最好快点，甜甜圈很快就没了
Whoa, that was close.
好险 !
Evil!
那恶!
Drive, drive, drive!
开车，开车 !
Oh, right.
对哦
Look at that. You can see the four states that border Springfield:
你能看到和春田市交界的四个州
Ohio, Nevada, Maine and Kentucky.
俄效俄、内华达、缅因、肯塔基
Oh, yeah.
对耶
And if you look real close, you can almost--
如果你仔细看，还可以看到…
Well, this certainly seems odd...
这有点怪，可是…
...but who am I to question the work of the Almighty?
我储什么质疑造物主的杰作 ?
We thank you, Lord, for this mighty fine intelligent design.
我们感谢你， 主啊 为你无比聪明的设计
Good job.
于得好
Jabbity, jabbity, jab, jab, jab!
我融、惟、蕉 !
Hey! Jab one more eye and it’s a federal crime.
再戳一次，你就犯了重罪
-Who are you? -Environmental Protection Agency.
-你是谁 ? -环境保护署
Russ Cargill, head of the EPA, here to see the president.
环保署长罗斯卡基' 请见总统
Mr. President.
阿诺总统
Ja, that is me.
路，我就是啦
Pollution in Springfield has reached crisis levels.
春田市的污染已形成危机
I hate this job. Everything's "crisis" this and "end of the world” that.
我真恨这个职位 每件事都是“危机、世界末日”
Nobody opens with a joke. I miss Danny DeVito.
没人讲笑话，我真想念丹尼狄维托
You want a joke, huh? Stop me if you've heard this one.
你想听笑话 ? 听过的话跟我说
Look at those angry eyes and giant teeth.
看看这些愤怒的眼睛和大尖牙
It’s like Christmas at the Kennedy compound.
就像圣诞节的装饰灯泡
You know, sir, when you made me head of the EPA...
长官，当你指派我为环保署长时
..-you appointed one of the most successful men in America...
你就是派了全美最成功的人之一
...to the least successful agency in government.
来主掌最失败的政府部门
And why did I take the job?
而我为什么接受这份工作呢 ?
Because I’m a rich man who wanted to give something back.
因为我是个想回馈社会的有钱人
Not the money, but something.
不是回馈钱 ' 而是别的
So here is our chance to kick some ass for Mother Earth.
所以这就是我们 为大自然复仇的机会
-I'm listening. -Well, I've narrowed your choices down...
-我在听 -我帮你把选项
...to five unthinkable options.
简化为五个离谱方案
Each will cause untold misery--
每一个都会引发无比的悲剧
l pick number three.
我选3号
You don’t wanna read them first?
你不想先看内容 ?
I was elected to lead, not to read. Number three!
人民选我来领导，不是来念书 就是3号
We're being sealed in a dome!
我们要被罩起来了
What do I do? I don’t know what to do!
我不知道该怎么办
If I stay, I'm trapped. If l leave, I'm alone.
留下就被困住，出去就孤单一人
I never saw Venice.
我还没去过威尼斯呢
"Trapped forever.”
“和余生受困”
It’s all come true.
全都实现了
That crazy old man in church was right.
教堂里那个老疯子说的是真的
Dome!
玻璃旱 !
All right, men, open fire.
好了“，大家开火 !
Who's hurt? Raise your hands.
谁受伤了 ? 快举手
Without the attitude.
真没用
People, people. Il have an important announcement.
各位，我有个重要的声明
l have just perfected an acid-firing super-drill...
我完美地改良了超级钻孔机
-...which can cut through anything. -Hey, that’s cool.
-能切割任何东西 -真酷
It’s right there.
它就在那里
Just outside of the dome.
就在黑子外面
What ruthless madmen could have done this to us?
是哪个疯子这样对待我们 ?
The United States government.
美国政府
My name is Russ Cargill and I'm head of the EPA.
我是环保署长罗斯卡基
The what?
什么长 ?
-Environmental Protection Agency. -Come again?
-环境保护署长 -再说一次
Look, I'm a man ona big TV. Just listen.
我是电视上的人，给我听着
-Springfield has become-- -Springfield!
-春田市已经成为… -春田市 !
--the most polluted city in the history of the planet.
地球史上污染最严重的城市
Drama queen!
爱现役 !
To keep your poisons from spreading...
为了控制你们的毒物
...your government has sealed you in this dome.
政府必须将你们四起来
it's the last thing we wanted to do.
我们并不想这么做
f own the company that makes the dome, but that's beside the point.
置子是我公司做的，但那不重要
You mean we're trapped like rats?
你是说我们像老鼠一样被关起来 ?
No, rats can't be trapped this easily. You're trapped like carrots.
不 ' 老鼠没这么好关 你们比较像是胡葛下
Wait. We couldn't be more polluted. Everyone stopped dumping in the lake.
等等，我们不可能有更多污染 大家都停止倒垃圾入湖了
Apparently someone didn't get the message.
有人明知改犯
Act natural.
表现自然点
Hey, buddy, sooner or later, people are gonna discover this.
老百姓迟早会发现这件事的
Don't worry about that. We found a way to take you off the map.
别担心，我们把春田市从地图拿掉了
Coming up on your right:
右侧即将抵达
Nothing.
一片空白
This is Kent Brockman, reporting to you on a crisis so serious...
(春田新闻 )
..it has its own name and theme music.
和主题音乐
The dome has put an end to life as we know it.
我们都知道圆顶已灭绝生机
The town is running low on supplies of everything from gasoline to Botox.
从汽油到肉毒杆菌 本城都缺货缺到爆
Moment, please.
请等一下
Now, as always, we end our news on "The Lighter Side.”
照惯例，我们以《欢乐新闻少 来做结尾
It's the time of year when the swallows return to Springfield.
一年一度燕子回春田市的日子到了
I think the thing I miss most is a simple summer breeze.
我想我最想念的就是夏日微风
Maggie?
媚姬 ?
We've got dome wax, dome polish, dome freshener, all your dome needs...
我们有贺顶蜡、圆项亮光剂 贺顶芳香剂，一切圆顶产品
.-.at Dome Depot, located at the 105 and the dome.
加项仓库都卖，就在圆项公路旁
Dome Depot!
加项仓库 !
Maggie got out! Maggie got out!
媚姬出去了 !
Maggie was right there, just outside the dome.
媚姬刚刚在那里 就在圆项外面
Marge, she’s right here.
玛姬，她在这里
This dome can play tricks on you. You just have to keep calm and--
这个圆顶会票人，要保持冷静
Oh, my God.
我的老天
I'm out of the dome. Fresh air! Freedom!
我出加项了“，新鲜空气 ! 自由 !
I'll write you. Lead good lives!
我会写信的，好好过日子
Good evening, this is Kent Brockman.
了晚安' 我是肯特布洛曼
Efforts to find out whose selfish crime caused our entrapment have been fruitless.
害我们被罩， 犯下滔天大罪的罪人 至今仍旧遂遥法外
Until moments ago!
不过不久之前
A shocking discovery has been made here at Lake Springfield.
春田湖有了惊人的发现
That could be anybody’s pig-crap silo.
那有可能是任何人的猪凑简
Homer, it was you.
荷马，是你
You single-handedly killed this town.
你一手害死了这个镇
I know. It’s weird.
我知道，这很怪
Just a reminder, this station does not endorse vigilante justice.
提醒您，本台并不赞成动用私刑
Unless it gets results. Which it will.
除非行动有明确目标，这很明确
You didn’t listen to me after l warned you.
我警告你了“，你还是不听
Don't worry, nobody watches this stupid show.
别担心，没人看这个策节目
What's that ominous glow in the distance?
远处不祥的光是什么 ?
KGL Kill KiHE
杀1I杀1I杀1I杀!
Marge, look. Those idiots don't even know where we live.
你看，这些笨疏不知道我们住哪
KGL Kill KiHE
杀1I杀1I杀!
We want Homer! We want Homer!
我们要荷马 ! 我们要荷马!
You monster. You monster!
怪物 ! 你这个怪物 !
Did you see the news?
你看到新闻了 ?
Honey, come on, we have bigger problems.
小乖，我们还有更大的问题
But I’m so angry.
不过， 我很生气
You're a woman. You can hold on to it forever.
你是女人，你可以忍一辈子
Okay.
好吧
Homer, you have to go out there, face that mob...
荷马，你得出去，面对群众
..and apologize for what you did.
为你的所作所为道歉
I would, but I'm afraid if 1 open the door, they'll take all of you.
我怕我一开门，他们会杀了你们
No, we won't. We just want Homer!
我们不会，我们只要和荷马
Well, maybe not you, but they'll kill Grampa.
可能不是杀你们 不过,他们会杀了区分
I'm part of the mob!
我在群众之中
Teeny! Take out the baby.
矮子，宣了那个宝宝
Here, let me get that for you.
我帮你点燃
Stay back. I got a chain saw.
退后 ! 我手上有链名
Bart!
霸子 !
Crawl across. Hurry.
由过来，快一点
But if they see you helping us, they'll kill you.
他们看到你帮有我们会杀了你
I'm sure your father would do the same for--
你父亲也一样会…
Point taken. Now, hustle your bustles.
知道了，快点行动吧
Archers.
弓箭手
I'm using a red arrow so I know who L kill.
我用红箭，这样才知道我杀了谁
No, Plopper. If you push that, Daddy will die.
不，哈利猪特 你乱推，老葡就死定了
Hey, my luck’s beginning to turn.
我开始转运了
Wait! There’s something I have to get.
等等，我有东西要拿
-What'd you get? -Our wedding video.
-你去拿什么 ? -我们结婚的录影带
-We have a wedding video? -Torch his gas tank!
-我们有结婚录影带 ? -烧了他的油箱
We lost them.
我们甩掉他们了
Up here.
上来
Get them! Get them!
捉住他们
Little help?
帮个忙吧
You know, the word “apology”...
你们知道，道痰这个字眼
...is tossed around a lot these days, but when it comes from in here--
最近都被滥用了 不过当诚意打从这里…
Mom, what are we gonna do?
妈，我们要怎么办 ?
Maggie, not now.
媚姬，现在不要
We'll play later.
待会再玩
The sinkhole. Follow me, kids!
淘空地基洞， 孩子们， 跟我来
-Geronimo! -Sacajawea!
-吉拉尼莫 -落卡嘉薇亚
So long, losers!
再见啦， 废物们
The top of his head is still showing. Claw at it!
他的头还露在外面，抓死他
Well, they’re China’s problem now.
他们现在是别国的问题了
Colin!
柯林
I can’t hear you!
我听不见你
I never thought my life would have an absolutely perfect moment, but this is--
我没想过我人生会有完美时刻 而这一刻…
Lisa’s got a boyfriend that she'll never see again!
莉莎交了男友， 以后都见不到
--perfect.
完美无瑕
-What do we do? -Now we run.
-我们该怎么办 ? -我们跑吧
I'm afraid we lost them, sir.
我们恐怕是追丢了
Damn it!
该死 !
Well, then, you find them and you get them back in the dome.
你去找他们， 把他们塞回圆顶
And so nobody else gets out...
不准再有人逃跑
..[ want roving death squads around the perimeter 24!7.
我要瞳杀团随时待命
I want 10,000 tough guys...
我要一万名坏人
..and I want 10,000 soft guys to make the tough guys look tougher.
跟一万名好人 好显示出坏人更坏
And here's how I want them arranged: Tough, tough, soft, tough...
我要这样安排他们
..- soft, soft, tough, tough, soft, soft, tough, soft.
好、好、坏、坏、好、好、坏、好
Sir, I'm afraid you've gone mad with power.
我想你是被权力给弄疯了
Of course. Ever try going mad without power? It’s boring. No one listens to you.
当然，没权力的少发疯 根本没人会听你的
-Bart, are you drinking whiskey? -I’m troubled.
-霸子，你喝威士忌 ? -我很烦
-Bart. -l promise, I'll stop tomorrow.
-霸子 -我明天就不喝了
You'll stop right now.
现在就不准喝
You come back here, little man.
你给我回来
I miss Flanders. There, I said it!
我想念佛朗德斯，我说出来了
-Where’s your father? -He went out.
-你爸呢 ? 他出去了
Let's quickly rebuild our lives while he’s gone.
我们快趁机重建我们的生活吧
Hey, guys?
各位
What's the secret knock, again?
再说一次密码是什么来着 ?
Look, I know I screwed up. This is big.
我知道我搞砸了“， 情况很粳
It's huge! We’re homeless!
是糟透了，我们无家可归
Our friends wanna kill us!
朋友们还想杀了我们
Before we can even stay in the same room with you...
在我们继续跟你同处一室之前
...[ need to know what was going through your mind...
我要知道你那时到底在想什么
...when you didn't listen to me...
当你完全没听我的话
..-and dumped that silo in the lake.
把那桶猪装丢进湖里时
Homer!
荷马!
I don’t know what to tell you, Marge. I don’t think about things.
我不知道该说什么 我什么都没想
l respect people who do...
我尊敬会想事情的人
...but I just try to make the days not hurt until get to crawl in next to you again.
不过， 我只是在聆上床躺在你身旁前 试着别搞磺事情
I mean, oh.
我是说，嗅
Look, I'm really sorry. But I’m more than just sorry...
我真的很抱歉 不过， 不只是抱火
...[’m prepared with a solution.
我还有解决方案
I've always been afraid I'd screw up our lives so badly we'd need a backup plan.
我一直怕我搞砸了我们的生活 搞到需要动用备用方案
And that plan is right here!
那个方案就在 这里
No.
不是
Nope.
也不是
Bingo.
有了 !
Bear with me.
丽一下
Alaska?
阿拉斯加 ?
Alaska. A place where you can't be too fat or too drunk.
阿拉斯加 ! 一个让你不会发胖柄酒的地方
Where no one says things like:
那里没有人会说
“Let's see your high school equivalency certificate.”
把你高中同等学历证明拿来看看
I don’t know, Homie.
我不知道哦，老荷马
I'm not saying it right.
我没说清楚
Look, the thing is, I can’t start a new life alone.
重点是，我无法独自展开新生活
And I’ve really come to like you guys.
而且我真的很喜欢你们
I just don't see it.
我就是无法想象
Marge, in every marriage, you get one chance to say:
玛姬，在婚姻之中总有人会说
"I need you to do this with me.”
“我需要你跟我一起来”
And there’s only one answer when somebody says that.
有人这么说时，答案只有一个
Okay, Homie, I'm with you.
好吧，我支持你
Thank you, my sweetheart.
谢谢你，我的甜心
-Mom? -Yes, honey?
-妈? -什么事 ?
You just bought another load of crap from the world’s fattest fertilizer salesman.
全世界最胖的废话推销员说的话 你竟然还买帐
You'll pay for ruining this golden family moment!
你破坏温馨时刻会付出代价的
Homer!
荷马!
How are we supposed to get to Alaska without any money?
我们没钱要怎么去阿拉斯加?
All right, son. If you don’t believe in me, believe in America.
很好,儿子 你不相信我，也要相信美国
America. Where any man can make quick money with no questions asked.
美国 任何人都能随便赚大钱的地方
Step right up and win my truck!
上来赢我的车吧
All you have to do is conquer the Ball of Death.
只要战胜死亡之球
-What’s the catch? -No catch.
-要要什么技巧 ? -不用要技巧
Just ride the motorcycle all the way around just one time.
只要骑车一口气绕一圈就行
Three tries for $10.
十元可以挑战三次
-Marge, how much money do we have? -Ten dollars.
-玛姬，我们有多少钱 ? 十元
That counts as a try.
那算一次
That's two.
那算第二次
And that's three.
那算第三次
Here’s what I'll do, because I like seeing you hurt yourself:
这样吧，由于我喜欢看你搞笑
I'll give you one on the house.
我再送你一次免费机会
-You're the best. -Dad!
-你太棒了 -区
When you get to the top, don't slow down, speed up!
你骑到项时 别慢下来，要加速 !
-But that’s when it’s the scariest. -Just do it!
-不过那里最丽怖啊 ! -照做就是
Yes!
太好了 !
Yay, Dad!
太棒了 ， 老答 !
Pll take that truck now.
我现在就要那台车
Oh, man. My wives are gonna kill me.
天哪，我老婆会地了我
Next stop, Alaska!
下一站，阿拉斯加
Day 37 under the dome.
圆顶罩头第3 7天
We are facing intermittent power failures which--
我们正面临间欢性的停电
Okay, very funny. I'm gonna turn the lights off again.
很好笑，我会再把灯关掉
When they come back on, l want all my booze back the way it was.
灯再开时 我要所有的酒回到原位
Yeah, okay. Okay.
是啊，好吧
I'm very proud of you, Bart. Over 24 hours sober.
我真是以你为荣，霸子 超过2 4小时没喝酒了
-You are, aren't you? -l'll prove it.
-对吧 ? -我会证明的
We're giving your father another chance, and we owe it to him to--
我们再给你父亲一次机会 我们欠他一次…
-Oh, my God. -Can I help you?
-胆，我的天 -需要什么吗 ?
We need diapers.
我们要尿片
-Okay. -No. No, we don’t. We don't.
-好 -不，我们不要
-Ladies’ razorblades. -Right.
-女士除毛刮 -好
No! No. No, we don't. I forgot, we’re European.
不 :我们不要 我忘了，我们是欧洲人
Just give us beef jerky.
给我们牛肉条就好
Lots and lots of beef jerky.
很多很多的牛肉条
That's right. That's what we need. That's all we came in for.
我们就需要那个 我们进来就是为了那个
Sure.
没问题
Oh, my God. There they are!
老天，是他们
So you want some of my electricity, do you?
你们想要我的电力， 是吧 ?
Well, for once, the rich white man is in control.
富有的白人终于掌握大权了
I have two buttons behind this desk.
这张桌子后面有两个按钮
One will supply your town with power, the other releases the hounds.
一个会供给你们镇上电力 另一个则是放狗蛟人
Reach me. Make me your brother.
跟我沟通，劝服我吧
The hospital's generator is about to give out.
医院的发电机快玩完了
Lives will be lost.
快死人了 !
"Lives lost." Go on.
“快死人了”
We got a convict we were gonna fry tomorrow, but now we can’t.
明天要处决犯人 电椅没电就不行了
Tempting. Tempting.
很吸引人了
Look, all our reasons mean nothing.
我们的理由都不算什么
Just look into your heart and you'll find the answer.
在你心里，你就能找到答案
-First door on the right. -Thank you.
-右边第一道门
What--? This isn’t the way l pictured Alaska at all!
这跟我想的阿拉斯加完全不同
Oh, that’s better.
好多了
Homer!
荷马
Well, at least my poster didn’t get torn.
至少我的海报没破
Welcome to Alaska. Here’s $1000.
欢迎莅临阿拉斯加，这是一千元
Well, it's about time! But why?
也该到了 ! 不过为什么 ?
We pay every resident $1000...
我们给所有居民一千元
...to allow oil companies to ravage our state’s natural beauty.
好让石油公司破坏这个天然美景
I'm home!
我到家了
What are you doing, Bart?
你在于嘛，霸子 ?
Just passing the time.
磨时间黑了
My boy loves Alaska so much, he’s applauding it.
我儿子太爱阿拉斯加 他在鼓掌庆祝
-Lisa, why aren't you clapping? -But, Dad--
-莉莎，你怎么不鼓掌 ? -可是 7 和葡…
Clap for Alaska!
为阿拉斯加鼓掌吧 !
Well, Marge, we're separated from the kids by a wall of snow.
玛姬，雪墙隔开了我们跟孩子
All my dreams are coming true.
我的美梦都成真了
We're going to need more birds.
我们需要更多乌
Day 93 under the dome.
圆顶罩头第9 3 天
With necessities growing dangerously low...
由于生活必需品所剩无几
...who knows what spark will set off this powder keg?
天知道什么情况会引发冲突 ?
-Let’s discuss Tuesdays with Morrie. -Again?
-来讨论《最后十四堂星期二的课》 -又讨论 ?
If we don’t get a new book, I'm going to puke.
再没有新书，我就要吐了
You're the five people I'm going to meet in hell!
你们是我在地狱会见到的五个人
We're out of coffee!
咖啡没了
I can’t take another minute in this dome!
我再也受不了这个圆顶了
Take that.
接招 !
Oh, no! Blowback!
嘱' 不! 回来
Look what they’re doing to our dome.
你看他们怎么搞我们的圆顶
You know what that is, sir?
你知道那是什么吗 ?
-A crack? -Exactly.
-裂痕? -没错
People got out of the dome before, they're gonna get out again.
之前有人光出加项 还会有人再逃出去
When they do, there’s gonna be hearings, investigations....
接着就会有听证、调查
I'll have to go back to making family comedies.
老天，我得回去拍家庭喜剧片了
Don't worry, I have a solution for you, sir. In fact, l have five solutions.
别担心，我有办法 事实上，我有五个办法
You don’t have to read them. You'll have deniability.
不用看，你会有否认权
I'll take care of it. You know nothing.
一切由我承担 你什么都不知道
No. I need to know what I’m approving.
我要知道我批准了什么
Absolutely. But on the other hand, knowing things is overrated.
当然，但相反地 知道太多也没好处
Anyone can pick something when they know what it is.
谁都可以选择他要知道的东西
It takes real leadership to pick something you're clueless about.
真正的领袖才有胆做宫目的选择
-Okay, I pick three. -Try again.
-好 ,我选3号 -再试一次
-One. Five? -Go higher. Too high.
-1号       -高一点 -5号? -太高了
-Three? -You said three.
-3号? -你选过了
-Six? Two? -There is no six. Double it.
-6号?     -没有6号 -2号?        -加倍
-Four! -As you wish, sir.
-4号 -如你所愿， 长官
Are you tired of the same old Grand Canyon?
你厌倦老旧的大峡谷了吗 ?
Here we are, kids, the Grand Canyon.
孩子们，我们到了…大峡谷
It’s so old and boring. I want a new one. Now!
又老旧又无聊 我要新的，就是现在
Hello. I'm Tom Hanks.
你好，我是汤姆汉克
The U.S. government has lost its credibility...
美国政府信誉尽失
...80 it’s borrowing some of mine.
所以他们跟我借
Tousle my hair, Mr. Hanks.
和拷乱我的头发，汉克先生
Sure thing, son.
没问题，孩子
Now, I'm pleased to tell you all about the New Grand Canyon.
我很高兴能告诉各位新大峡谷的事
This weekend. East of Shelbyville and south of Capitol City.
就在这个周末，就会出现在 雪身镇以东' 首府市以南之处
That's where Springfield is!
春田市就在那里
It’s nowhere near where anything is or ever was.
这里并不靠近现在或以前的任何地方
This is Tom Hanks, saying:
我是汤姆汉克“，我说
If you're going to pick a government to trust, why not this one?
要选可信的政府，何不选这个 ?
Did you see that?
你们看到没 ?
Yes, they're going to destroy Springfield.
他们要摧毁春田市
But we're going to stop them.
不过我们要阻止他们
Homie, get your clothes on. Homie?
荷马，快穿衣服 ' 荷马 ?
I'm happy here. Screw Springfield!
我在这里很快乐 去他的春田市
I can't believe you'd say something so selfish.
我真不敢相信你竟然这么自私
Marge, those people chased us with pitchforks and torches.
那些人拿和竹子和火把追我们
Torches! At 4 in the afternoon!
火把 ! 在下午四点的时候
-It was 7 at night. -It was during Access Hollywood.
-那时是晚上七点 -那时在播《前进好莱坞》
Which is on at 4 and 7.
那四点和七点都有播
Dad, how can you turn your back on everyone who loved us?
和爸， 你怎能背弃爱我们的人 ?
Flanders helped when we were in trouble.
我们有麻烦时，佛朗德斯帮了忙
Who cares what he did? He’s not your father.
谁在乎 ? 他又不是你爸
I wish he was.
我真希望他是
You don’t mean that. You worship me.
你不是认真的，你崇拜我
Oh, yeah? Look what I did to your picture.
是吗 ? 看我怎么画你的照片 ?
Look at it.
你看
How-dilly-doo-dilly. How-dilly-doo-dilly.
你好啊
Why, you little--!
你这个小…
I'll strangle-angle you!
我要勒死你
Diddily-diddily.
我好得很
Bart, stop it! Leave this to me.
霸子，别插手，让我来
Homer...
荷马
. . . In every marriage, you get one chance to say:
在婚姻之中总有人会说
"I need you to do this with me.”
“我需要你跟我一起来”
That is the stupidest thing I’ve ever heard.
那是我听过最蠢的话了
Homer Simpson!
荷马辛普森
We're saving Springfield!
我们要拯救春田市 !
Listen to me, all of you. We are staying.
听我说，我们要留下来
We have a great life in Alaska...
我们在阿拉斯加过得很好
..and we're never going back to America again.
我们不要再回美国去了
l have spoken!
我已经说过了
Well, I guess I’ve let her worry about me long enough.
我想我让她担心得够久了
Marge? Kids?
玛姬 ? 孩子们 ?
Okay, here goes.
好,开始了
Homer...
荷马
...1've always stood up for you.
我一向支持你
When people point out your flaws...
当人们指出你的缺点时
...f always say:
我总是说
"Well, sometimes you have to stand back to appreciate a work of art."
“有时你得往后站才能欣赏艺术品”
Way back.
站很后面
Lately, what's keeping us together...
最近，维系我们的
...is my ability to overlook everything you do.
只是我宽容你所作所为的能力
And I overlook these things because....
而我宽容你的所作所为，是因为…
Because?
因为?
Well, that's the thing.
问题就在那里
f just don't know how to finish that sentence anymore.
我不再知道该怎么结束这名话了
So I'm leaving with the kids to help Springfield...
所以我跟孩子离开 去帮助春田市
..and we're never coming back.
我们也不会回来了
And to prove to myself that this is the end...
为了向我自己证明一切结束了
...f taped this over our wedding video.
我拿我们婚礼的带子来录影
Goodbye, Homie.
再见，老公
f love you.
我爱你
Marge? Kids?
玛姬 ? 孩子们 ?
-So, Mom, what's our plan? -What are you doing up there?
-我们有什么计划 ? -你在上面于嘛 ?
Looking through people’s luggage.
翻别人的行李
I'm the mascot of an evil corporation.
我是那恶企业的吉祥物
Get down from there. We have to keep a low profile...
快点下来，我们得保持低调
...till we get to Seattle to tell the world of the plot to destroy Springfield.
直到我们抵达西雅图 向全世界揭露摧毁春田市的阴谋
I don’t know if you guys should be talking so loud.
你们不该大声说话
Oh, Lisa, it's not like the government is listening to everybody's conversation.
革莎，政府又没有 监听每个人说话
Hi, I'm calling about your Meat Lover's pizza.
我想说说你的恋爱嫩肉披萨
i like meat, but 1 don’t know if {'m ready to love again.
我喜欢肉，不过， 我还不想谈恋爱
-You hang up first. -No, you hang up first.
-你先挂 -不，你先挂
Okay.
好吧
She hung up on mef
她挂我电话 !
But we're fugitives. We should just lay low till we get to Seattle.
不过我们是逃犯 我们该低调点，直到抵达西雅图
Hey, everybody, I found one!
各位，我找到了
The government actually found someone we're looking for!
政府真的找到我们要找的人了
Yeah, baby, yeah!
好啊 !
Homer Simpson...
荷马辛普森
...do you know why you are here?
你知道你为什么会在这里吗 ?
Because my family cares more about other people than they do about me.
因为我的家人关心别人甚于我
Drink this liquid.
喝了这杯
More, please.
再来
Now we will cleanse your spirit...
现在我们用古伊努特的驱歌法
...by the ancient Inuit art of throat singing.
来洁净你的灵魂
Throat singing?
驱歌法 ?
How long are we doing this?
我们要这么做多久 ?
-Until you have an epiphany. -Okay.
-到你领悟为目 -好吧
What's an epiphany?
什么是领悟 ?
Sudden realization of great truth.
突然明白真正的事实
Okay.
好吧
Spider-Pig, Spider-Pig
蜂蛛猪、蜂蛛猪
Does whatever a Spider-Pig does
蜂蛛猪行侠仗义
Look out!
小心  1
He's a Spider-Pig
它是蜘蛛猪
Unless you have an epiphany...
除非你有了领悟
...you will spend the remainder of your days alone.
否则你将终身孤独
Bananas are an excellent source of potassium.
香基富含钊
Americans will never embrace soccer?
美国人永远不会爱踢足球 ?
More than two shakes and it’s playing with yourself?
甩小弟弟超过两次也算数 ?
Hey, what are you doing?
你们在于嘛 ?
Oh, do whatever you want to me. I don't care about myself anymore.
随便你了“， 我已经无所谓了
Because...?
因为?
Because other people are just as important as me.
因为其他人跟我一样重要
Without them, I’m nothing.
没有他们“，我什么都不是
In order to save myself...
为了拯救我自己
...[ have to save Springfield!
我得拯救春田市
That's it! Isn't it?
这就是了 ! 对不对 ?
That was the most incredible experience of my life.
那是我这辈子最不可思议的体验
And now to find my family, save my town and drop 10 pounds!
现在去找我的家人、拯救我的镇 还有减肥十磅
Thank you, boob lady.
谢谢你， 波霸婆
This is it, kids. Seattle.
到了“， 孩子们 ' 西雅图
Russ Cargill! Do you think he saw us?
环保署长，他看见我们了吗 ?
Yes, I did.
我是看见了
Run! Run!
快跑 ! 快跑 !
Jump! Jump!
跳!跳 !
Land! Land!
着地 ! 着地 !
Rest! Rest!
休息 ! 休息!
Run! Run!
快跑 ! 快跑 !
Now, I know we've had a rough day...
我知道我们今天累坏了
...but I'm sure we can put all that behind us and--
不过，让我们将一切抛在脑后
That's my whipping arm!
那是我挥对子的手
Why does everything I whip leave me?
为何我鞭打的一切都离我而去 ?
No, I can’t. I can’t keep going.
不，我做不到， 我走不动了
Yes, you can.
你可以的
No, I can’t!
我做不到
Oh, shut up!
闭嘴呼 !
You shut up.
你才闭嘴 !
No, you. No, you.
不' 是你 ! 不' 是你!
No, you. Oh, real mature.
不， 是你 ! 你还真成熟啊
How could you say that?
你怎能那么说 ?
Oh, what's the point?
有什么用?
It's hopeless.
没指望了
Don’t give up, Homer. You are closer than you think.
别放弃，和荷马 你比你想的还要接近
But which way do I go?
可是我该往哪里走 ?
Much obliged.
感恩啦
Ten-hut!
立正!
Lisa! Knock off that racket.
莉莎，别吹了
They captured my family. What do I do? What do I do?
他们捉了我家人 ? 我该怎么办 ?
There's something strange about that "sop" sign.
那个停的标志有点怪
-Did you hear something? -Probably just a moth.
-你们有没有听见什么 ? -可能是飞蛾吧
l hope it’s okay.
希望它没事
Look, we can't keep stopping at every "sop," "yeld" or “one vay” sign.
我们不能看到什么标志都售
Just move on.
快点上路吧
Let us out! Let us out!
放我们出去
Stop that. You'll scratch your shackles.
别阅了，你会乔花手铸的
l hope I do.
我正希望如此
Oh, way to go, Bart.
你真行啊，霸子
You stink.
你真恶心
No, you stink.
你才恶心呢
Springfield.
春田市 !
I can't believe it, but it got even crappier.
我真不敢相信 不过它变得更破烂了
Oh, man.
天哪
Oh, hi, Midge.
你好，玛姬
Moe, what happened?
摩伊 ， 怎么回事 ?
With the town sealed off from the rest of the world, things got a little nutty here.
整个镇被隔离之后 事情变得有点疯狂
Why are you dressed like that?
你为什么穿成那样 ?
Well, I don't like to brag, but 1 am now the emperor of Springfield.
我不喜欢自夸 不过， 我现在是春田国王
No, you're not!
不，你不是
Yes, 1 am!
我是
Okay. Hail, emperor.
好有吧“，国王万岁
Attention, Springfield.
春田市注意
Your government has realized that putting you inside this dome was a terrible mistake.
你们的政府明白 将你们用圆顶轩起来是错的
Therefore, we're commencing with Operation Soaring Eagle.
所以我们要展开飞诬行动
Which involves killing you alt.
目标是歼灭你们
As ! speak, we're lowering a small but powerful bomb into your midst.
我们要放一个小又够力的炸弹
Despite everything, I miss your father.
尽管发生这些事 我还是想念你们的老区
Me too.
我也是
His big, fat ass could shield us all.
他的肥屁股可以帮有我们挡炸弹
Ten-hut!
立正!
At ease. I'm General Marriott Suites...
稍息，我是希尔顿将军
..and I have an urgent note from the president.
我收到总统撒来的急电
It says to release this town immediately.
电文上说要立刻释放此镇
Why is it written on a leaf?
那为什么会写在一片叶子上 ?
Perfect.
太棒了
Now Homer Simpson’s gonna show he has cojones!
这下荷马要展现他超级带种的能力
Mom, I've gotta go find Colin.
妈，我要去找柯林
Not now, sweetie. Doomsday is family time.
现在不行，女儿 末日是家人团聚的时刻
Hey. If one of us distracts Cargill, the rest of us can climb up that thing.
若我们有人能引开卡基的注意力 其他人就能疏上那里
Who'd be dumb enough to stay behind while we escape with our lives?
谁会策到在我们逃走时留下来 ?
My time to shine.
该我露脸了
Hey, Mr. Big TV Man, lookie here!
大电视人，看这里
What do you want?
你要什么 ?
Look what I can do with my thumb.
你看我的手指
You wanna know how I do it?
想知道我怎么办到的吗 ?
Four generations of inbreeding?
四代的近亲繁殖 ?
I can smell fresh air.
我能闻到新鲜空气了
I can hear birds.
我能听到乌岂了
I taste freedom.
我尝到自由的滋味了
Excuse me! Watch out! Coming through!
抱歉 ! 小心点，要来嚼
! was tricked by an idiot.
我被一个策疏骗了
Hey, I know how you feel. l was beat in tic-tac-toe by a chicken.
我知道你的感受 我玩井字游戏还输给小鸡
Goodbye.
再见
Homer do good?
荷马立大功?
Actually, you doomed us all. Again. Nice knowing you, Homer.
其实， 你又害惨我们了 认识你真好， 和荷马
But l....
但是我…
I can’t do anything right.
我做什么都会出错
Get out of here!
滚出去
I've spent my entire life doing nothing but collecting comic books.
我一辈子只知道搜集漫画
And now there's only time to say:
现在我只能说
Life well spent!
于得好 !
Okay, boys. When you meet Jesus, be sure to call him Mr. Christ.
等你们见到敢稣时 记得要叫他基督先生
Will Buddha be there too?
佛祖也会在那里吗 ?
No.
不会!
-Hey, Flanders. -Bart.
-嘿，佛朗德斯 -霸子
How good to see you. And how terrible you're here.
看到你真好，可惜你在这里
Thanks.
谢了
Listen. 1 was just wondering if...
听着，我本来在想
...before I died...
在我死之前
...l could pretend I had a father who...
能不能假装我有个
...cared for me.
在乎我的父亲
Come here, son.
过来吧，孩子
There’s always room for one more in the Flanders clan.
佛朗德斯家永远有位置留给你
Come on, bomb-disarming robot. You're our last hope.
快点， 拆炸弹机器人 你是我们最后的希望
Red wire. Blue wire. Black is usually the ground.
红线、蓝线，黑线通常是接地线
So much pressure.
压力好大
Pressure!
压力!
He'd been talking about it, but I didn’t take him seriously.
它提过很多次了，可是我没当真
Marge.
玛姬
Marge! Marge!
玛姬 ! 玛姬 !
Oh, no, the "epipha-tree"!
不， 领悟树
Hey, I tried my best. What am I supposed to do?
我尽力了，我该怎么办 ?
But how am I supposed to get up there?
可是我要怎么限上那里 ?
Here. Buy yourself something nice.
拿去，给自己买点吃的
Homer? What the hell are you doing now?
荷马 ? 你这是在于嘛 ?
Risking my life to save people I hate...
为了我不大懂的原因
...for reasons I don't quite understand. Gotta go!
冒生命危险去救我讨厌的人 我得走了
But first, one stop.
不过，要先去一个地方
Bart? Son?
霸子?儿子?
You think you could find it in your heart...
能不能再给你的
...to give your foolish old man one more chance?
答老爸一次机会 ?
Oh, I don’t know.
我不知道哦
It seems to me, son, that your father’s saying that...
在我看来，你父亲是说
...he wants to spend his last minute with you.
他想跟你共度最后的时光
No. I can’t do it.
不 我做不到
l want a father who’s the same in the morning as he is at night.
我要一个从时到了晚都一样的老爸
What's that word?
那叫什么来着 ?
-Consistency.
-表里一致
Thanks, losers.
谢了，小策蛋
Sorry, Homer.
对不起，和荷马
I'll let you hold the bomb.
我让你拿炸弹
The man knows me.
这家伙在烦我
l wish Homer was my father.
我真希望荷马是我爸
And I wish you didn’t have the devil's curly hair.
我希望你没有那头那恶的卷发
I've been taking your crap all my life!
我一辈子都受你欺负
This feels good. No wonder you do it.
感觉真好，难怪你爱这样
Okay, you've only got one shot to throw that bomb through the hole.
你有一次机会将炸弹丢出洞外
Dad, in case I miss...
和爸，万一我失手
...[’m sorry I said 1 wished you weren't my father.
我很抱歉曾说过希望你不是我爸
I don't blame you, son. l wasn’t much of a father.
我不怪你，我本来就不是好答爸
Maybe it starts with the way my dad raised me.
也许那是因为我从也没好好养我
Yes. It’s clear to me. It’s just been one long, unbroken cycle of--
是啊， 一切都很明白 这是个漫长又牢不可破的…
Somebody throw the goddamn bomb!
快把那该死的炸弹扔了
What? What's going on?
什么 ?怎么回事 ?
We did it, boy!
我们成功了
Dad?
和爸?
It’s amazing no one was hurt.
没人受伤，还真是奇迹
Bye, everybody.
再见了，各位
Now, that was a great father-son activity.
那是精彩的父子联手
Hello, Homer.
你好，和荷马
So we meet at last, whoever you are.
我们终于见面了 不管你是谁
There's two things they don’t teach you at Harvard Business School.
哈佛商学院有两件事不会教
How to cope with defeat, and how to handle a shotgun.
如何面对失败和如何使用猎枪
I'm going to do both right now.
我现在要同时做这两件事
Wait! If you kill my dad...
等等，要是你杀了我区
..-you'll never know where the treasure is buried.
你就不会知道宝藏埋在哪里了
What treasure?
什么宝藏 ?
The Treasure of Imawiener.
你是香肠宝藏
I'm a wiener?
我是香肠?
Classic.
真经典
Well, always leave them laughing.
临死还要愁搞
Goodbye, sir.
再见了
Maggie! What a great little accident you turned out to be.
媚姬，你真是最意外的小惊喜
Colin? Colin!
柯林 ? 柯林 !
Lisa? Colin’s dead.
革莎 ? 柯林死了
But his last words were:
他留下来的遗言是
“Milhouse, take care of Lisa. Hold her hand.”
握紧她的手”
I got her all warmed up for you.
我帮你暖好场子了
Colin. Hi.
柯林，临
-Hey, you wanna go--? -Clean up the lake?
-你想不想去… ? -清理春田湖 ?
Well, was gonna say get some ice cream, but okay.
我本来想说去吃冰湛淋的 不过这个也可以啦
I like ice cream.
我喜欢吃冰淇淋
Kind of sweaty. Sorry.
有点手汗，抱雪
Boy! You survived! How?
小帮手 ! 你没死 ! 怎么会 ?
I did things no dog should do.
我做了狗不该做的事
They will haunt me forever.
这会永远纠缠着我
l love you too.
我也爱你
Best kiss of my life.
我这辈子最棒的一个吻
Best kiss of your life so far.
是到目前为止最棒的吻
Steady.
稳住
Dad?
和爸?
Thanks, boy.
谢了,儿子
Steady.
稳住
They've taken everything, sir.
他们把一切都拿走了
Smithers, I don’t believe in suicide...
史密瑟，我不鼓励自杀
...but if you'd like to try it, it might cheer me up to watch.
不过若你想试试 我可能会很高兴
This is Tom Hanks, saying:
我是汤姆汉克“，我说
If you see me in person, please, leave me be.
如果你看到我本人，别打扰我
Spider-Pig, Spider-Pig
蜂蛛猪、蜂蛛猪
Does whatever a Spider-Pig does
蜂蛛猪行侠仗义
Can he swing from a web?
它能挂在蜂蛛网上摇摆吗 ?
No, he can't, he's a pig
不行 它是猪
Look out!
小心
He is a Spider-Pig
它是蜘蛛猪
Come on, Dad, let’s go. I’ve been holding it since they put the dome over the town.
和爸, 走啦 我从圆顶量下来时巾到现在
You can wait. A lot of people worked really hard on this film...
等等，很多人努力参与制作本片
...and all they ask is for you to memorize their names.
他们只求你记得他们的名字
Well, ! wanna make sure no animals were harmed during the filming of this movie.
我只想确保拍片期间 没有动物受伤
Okay.
好吧
Wait, wait, wait! It looks like Maggie has something to say.
等等，媚姬似乎有话要说
Oh, my God. Her first word.
老天， 她开口说的第一个字
Sequel?
续集 ?
Springfield doesn't have an anthem
春田市没有市歌
We thought we had one But we don't
我们以为有， 其实没有
We paid a short guy to write it
我们请一个矮子写歌
But we never saw him again
但却再也不见他人影
The tune we stole from the French
我们偷用法国的曲子
There's a few things they do well
法国有些东西真不错
Like making love, wine and cheese
父亲亲、红酒和乳酷
Like Roqueforts, Camemberts and Bries
羊乳王酷、软质于酷和白于酷
Springfield, we're going to die
春田，我们死定了
Springfield, {'m scared, goodbye
春田，我好怕，再见
Assistant manager isn’t all it's cracked up to be.
做副理不如抬头风光
Four years of film school for this?
念四年电影学校就做这个 ?
[ENGLISH]
多谢观赏 剧终